<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<component type="desktop">
    <id>io.dbeaver.DBeaverCommunity</id>
    <launchable type="desktop-id">io.dbeaver.DBeaverCommunity.desktop</launchable>
    <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
    <project_license>Apache-2.0</project_license>
    <name>DBeaver Community</name>
    <url type="homepage">https://dbeaver.io</url>
    <url type="bugtracker">https://github.com/dbeaver/dbeaver/issues</url>
    <summary>Universal Database Manager.</summary>
    <description>
        <p>Free multi-platform database tool for developers, SQL programmers, database administrators and analysts. Supports all popular databases: MySQL, PostgreSQL, MariaDB, SQLite, Oracle, DB2, SQL Server, Sybase, MS Access, Teradata, Firebird, Derby, etc.</p>
        <p>This is the official build of DBeaver, packaged into a Flatpak. This repackaging is not supported by DBeaver Community Edition.</p>
    </description>
    <screenshots>
        <screenshot type="default">
            <image>https://i.imgur.com/AiCETK9.png</image>
            <caption>Query properties overview</caption>
        </screenshot>
        <screenshot>
            <image>https://i.imgur.com/5S6ohkF.png</image>
            <caption>Query properties overview</caption>
        </screenshot>
        <screenshot>
            <image>https://i.imgur.com/0a4OyvB.png</image>
            <caption>Query search overview</caption>
        </screenshot>
        <screenshot>
            <image>https://i.imgur.com/neoEtsF.png</image>
            <caption>ER Diagram Example</caption>
        </screenshot>
    </screenshots>
    <releases>
        <release version="7.2.1" date="2020-09-20">
            <description>
                <p>Preference pages structure was reorganized (in the standalone and plugin versions)</p>
                <p>Database navigator:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>Filters now support masks escape (_ and % characters)</li>
                    <li>Connection state icons were replaced and adapted to dark themes</li>
                </ul>
                <p>SQL Editor: editor tab title now can include active database/schema name</p>
                <p>MySQL: driver "MySQL 8" is now the default driver. "MySQL 5" driver can be used for older server versions.</p>
                <p>Oracle: tables/views load performance was improved on some systems</p>
                <p>PostgreSQL:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>Latest PostGIS driver mapping was added</li>
                    <li>Geometry data types export was improved (proper SQL format + SRID)</li>
                    <li>Hidden databases can be loaded in the database navigater </li>
                </ul>
                <p>CockroarchDB: role manager was fixed</p>
                <p>DB2: runstats utility support was fixed (wrong syntax)</p>
                <p>SQL Server: extra T-SQL dialect keywords were added</p>
                <p>CUBRID driver configuration was fixed</p>
                <p>Several UI freeze issues were fixed (deadlocks)</p>
                <p>Import from CSV/XLSX:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>Wrong rows can be skipped (with disabled "Batch import" option)</li>
                    <li>Import parameters documentation was updated </li>
                </ul>
                <p>Several minor bugs were fixed (NPE and UI glitches) </p>
            </description>
            <url>https://github.com/dbeaver/dbeaver/releases/tag/7.2.1</url>
        </release>
        <release version="7.2.0" date="2020-08-30">
            <description>
                <p>Major changes since 7.1:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>Simplified database structure view was added</li>
                    <li>Database maintenance tools can be saved as tasks now</li>
                    <li>Table and schema size statistics were added in the database navigator</li>
                    <li>Import from multiple CSV files was added. Files can be imported into new or existing tables</li>
                    <li>Many problems with UI freeze on disconnect or query cancel were fixed</li>
                    <li>Database navigator rendering was redesigned</li>
                    <li>A number of problems with keyboard shortcuts were fixed</li>
                    <li>Git integration was improved: now we show file status in the Project Explorer view</li>
                    <li>New database drivers were added: YugabyteDB and SQreamDB</li>
                </ul>
                <p>Changes since 7.1.5:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>Problem with database list load was fixed (PostgreSQL, Redshift, MySQL, Oracle, SQL Server)</li>
                    <li>Metadata editor: edit property form rendering was improved (non-applicable fields are hidden)</li>
                    <li>Performance for table statistics reading was improved</li>
                    <li>Data viewer: Column ordering was fixed (for custom SQL queries). UUID transform: version 2 support was added</li>
                    <li>Default database name and default user name were added for many database drivers</li>
                    <li>Data export: custom data type formatting support was fixed</li>
                    <li>PostgreSQL: Cursor fetch was fixed. Native client was upgraded to version 12. Table OID support was fixed (PG 12). PgPass parser was improved (support for escaped characters was added).</li>
                    <li>Oracle: Materialized view comment editor was fixed. View definition reading was fixed (for non-DBA users). Table reading now uses DBA views (optional). Profile resources metadata reading was fixed.</li>
                    <li>MariaDB/MySQL: table column resolving was fixed</li>
                    <li>CockroachDB: connectivity problem was fixed</li>
                    <li>Greenplum: Metadata search was fixed (for procedures). Table metadata reading was fixed.</li>
                    <li>Dark theme support was improved (tab folders, toolbars)</li>
                    <li>A large number of minor UI bugfixes</li>
                </ul>
            </description>
            <url>https://github.com/dbeaver/dbeaver/releases/tag/7.2.0</url>
        </release>
        <release version="7.1.5" date="2020-08-16">
            <description>
                <p>Data transfer:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>Import from multiple CSV files was added</li>
                    <li>Import from files into new tables</li>
                    <li>Data import preview dialog was added</li>
                    <li>Target table create/alter DDL now supports database-specific options</li>
                    <li>Virtual columns are ignored in SQL INSERTs export</li>
                    <li>Problem with data transfer wizard and Darkest Dark theme was fixed</li>
                    <li>Problem with timestamp format for CSV/XLSX export was fixed</li>
                    <li>Case sensitive table/column names resolution was fixed</li>
                </ul>
                <p>Database navigator:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>Statistics render was fixed for MacOS and Linux</li>
                    <li>Database size statistics was added for PostgreSQL, MySQL, SQL Server, DB2</li>
                </ul>
                <p>Team work:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>Problem with empty Git Repositories view was fixed</li>
                    <li>Git integration was added in project navigator view</li>
                </ul>
                <p>PostgreSQL:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>Native client version was upgraded to version 12 (Windows)</li>
                    <li>Check constraints read was fixed (PG 12+)</li>
                    <li>SQL results limit was fixed (for queries with LIMIT/OFFSET/FETCH clauses)</li>
                    <li>Object DDL generator was improved (comments, permissions)</li>
                    <li>Support of case insensitive full-text search was added</li>
                    <li>Table partitions statistics was added</li>
                </ul>
                <p>Oracle:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>TNS names search was fixed</li>
                    <li>Connection info was fixed for TNS/custom URL connections</li>
                    <li>Variables are now supported in custom JDBC URL (thanks to @insightfuls)</li>
                </ul>
                <p>MySQL:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>Problem with check constraints read was fixed</li>
                    <li>Table copy was fixed (bug with redundant indexes was resolved)</li>
                </ul>
                <p>Redshift: problem with read-only resultsets was fixed.
                    Snowflake: SQL dialect support was fixed ($$ comments).
                    A large number of minor UI improvements and bugfixes</p>
            </description>
            <url>https://github.com/dbeaver/dbeaver/releases/tag/7.1.5</url>
        </release>
        <release version="7.1.4" date="2020-08-02">
            <description>
                <p>Release of version: 7.1.4</p>
            </description>
            <url>https://github.com/dbeaver/dbeaver/releases/tag/7.1.4</url>
        </release>
        <release version="7.1.3" date="2020-07-19">
            <description>
                <p>Release of version: 7.1.3</p>
            </description>
            <url>https://github.com/dbeaver/dbeaver/releases/tag/7.1.3</url>
        </release>
        <release version="7.1.2" date="2020-07-05">
            <description>
                <p>Data viewer:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>Now we refresh entire row after cell value update (handy if you have triggers)</li>
                    <li>Generate SQL context menu was fixed</li>
                    <li>Horizontal scroll with mouse wheel support was added</li>
                    <li>Export data in source code (PHP arrays) format was added</li>
                    <li>Bug with Ctrl+Backspace handler was fixed</li>
                </ul>
                <p>SQL Editor:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>Query cancel handler was improved (problem with UI stuck was fixed)</li>
                    <li>Now we show query information in the result tab tooltip</li>
                    <li>Query parser was fixed (active query extraction for Ctrl+Enter action)</li>
                    <li>Template variables (${word_selection} and ${line_selection}) support was fixed</li>
                </ul>
                <p>Navigator:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>Icons for "Create object" actions were fixed</li>
                    <li>Main menu File items were reordered</li>
                    <li>Heading and trailing spaces trim was added to all edit dialogs/panels</li>
                </ul>
                <p>Session manager: problem with multiple windows was fixed.
                SQL Server: Database tools (index rebuild, triggers disable) were redesigned.
                Firebird: new table and table column creation was fixed.
                PostgreSQL: Table partition DDL was fixed.
                MySQL: CHECK constraints edit support was added</p>
                <p>Oracle:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>Table statistics read was fixed</li>
                    <li>Schema indexes folder was added</li>
                    <li>Check constraints editor was added</li>
                    <li>Trigger status icon was fixed</li>
                </ul>
                <p>Exasol: (thanks to @Sargul)</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>Metadata read performance was improved</li>
                    <li>Metadata search support was added</li>
                    <li>Table references</li>
                    <li>Index create DDL was fixed</li>
                    <li>Table statistics read performance was improved</li>
                </ul>
                <p>Redshift: driver download was fixed.
                SQreamDB driver was added.
                YugabyteDB driver was added.
                We upgraded Eclipse platform version to 2020-06. It affects dark theme and General preferences and fixes several minor bugs</p>
            </description>
        </release>
    </releases>
    <content_rating type="oars-1.1"/>
</component>