<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<component type="desktop">
    <id>io.dbeaver.DBeaverCommunity</id>
    <launchable type="desktop-id">io.dbeaver.DBeaverCommunity.desktop</launchable>
    <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
    <project_license>Apache-2.0</project_license>
    <name>DBeaver Community</name>
    <url type="homepage">https://dbeaver.io</url>
    <url type="bugtracker">https://github.com/dbeaver/dbeaver/issues</url>
    <summary>Universal Database Manager.</summary>
    <description>
        <p>Free multi-platform database tool for developers, SQL programmers, database administrators and analysts. Supports all popular databases: MySQL, PostgreSQL, MariaDB, SQLite, Oracle, DB2, SQL Server, Sybase, MS Access, Teradata, Firebird, Derby, etc.</p>
        <p>This is the official build of DBeaver, packaged into a Flatpak. This repackaging is not supported by DBeaver Community Edition.</p>
    </description>
    <screenshots>
        <screenshot type="default">
            <image>https://i.imgur.com/AiCETK9.png</image>
            <caption>Query properties overview</caption>
        </screenshot>
        <screenshot>
            <image>https://i.imgur.com/5S6ohkF.png</image>
            <caption>Query properties overview</caption>
        </screenshot>
        <screenshot>
            <image>https://i.imgur.com/0a4OyvB.png</image>
            <caption>Query search overview</caption>
        </screenshot>
        <screenshot>
            <image>https://i.imgur.com/neoEtsF.png</image>
            <caption>ER Diagram Example</caption>
        </screenshot>
    </screenshots>
    <releases>
        <release version="7.2.5" date="2020-11-15">
            <description>
                <p>Release of version: 7.2.5</p>
            </description>
            <url>https://github.com/dbeaver/dbeaver/releases/tag/7.2.5</url>
        </release>
        <release version="7.2.4" date="2020-11-01">
            <description>
                <p>Release of version: 7.2.4</p>
            </description>
            <url>https://github.com/dbeaver/dbeaver/releases/tag/7.2.4</url>
        </release>
        <release version="7.2.3" date="2020-10-18">
            <description>
                <p>Release of version: 7.2.3</p>
            </description>
            <url>https://github.com/dbeaver/dbeaver/releases/tag/7.2.3</url>
        </release>
        <release version="7.2.2" date="2020-10-04">
            <description>
                <p>Release of version: 7.2.2</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>
                  Database navigator:
                        <ul>
                            <li>View only connected data sources filter was added</li>
                            <li>Quick search in connections/schemas options were added</li>
                            <li>Multiple objects delete confirmation dialog was redesigned</li>
                            <li>Tooltips visibility configuration was added in preferences</li>
                        </ul>
                    </li>
                    <li>Windows installer: shortcuts for "All Users" were fixed</li>
                    <li>
                  SSH tunnels:
                        <ul>
                            <li>Support for OpenSSH key format was added</li>
                            <li>Problem with dobule password prompt was fixed</li>
                        </ul>
                    </li>
                    <li>
                  Data viewer:
                        <ul>
                            <li>Grouping panel now supports column reordering</li>
                            <li>Column modifier icons (key, read-only) were updated</li>
                            <li>JSON/XML viewer performance was significantly improved</li>
                        </ul>
                    </li>
                    <li>SQL editor: toolbar buttons enablement was fixed</li>
                    <li>
                  Data transfer:
                        <ul>
                            <li>Native client selector was fixed</li>
                            <li>Extra file name pattern variables were added</li>
                            <li>Native date/timestamp format support was added to the SQL INSERTS export</li>
                            <li>Extra formatting options were added to the SQL INSERTS format</li>
                        </ul>
                    </li>
                    <li>MySQL: user credentials of mysqldump overwrite local configuration now</li>
                    <li>
                  SQL Server:
                        <ul>
                            <li>SSL support was added</li>
                            <li>Database create/drop/rename features were added</li>
                        </ul>
                    </li>
                    <li>
                  PostgreSQL:
                        <ul>
                            <li>Interval data type DDL was improved</li>
                            <li>Table storage parameters were added to DDL</li>
                            <li>"Connect as role" option was added in the connection settings</li>
                            <li>Materialized view comment edit was fixed</li>
                            <li>Trigger comment editor was added</li>
                        </ul>
                    </li>
                    <li>Oracle: extra NLS parameters were added on the connection settings page</li>
                    <li>Snowflake: active schema set command was fixed</li>
                    <li>Derby: unique indexes metadata read was implemented</li>
                    <li>SQLite: column autoincrement option support was added</li>
                    <li>Firebird: data types information read was fixed</li>
                    <li>Several other minor UI bugs were fixed</li>
                </ul>
            </description>
            <url>https://github.com/dbeaver/dbeaver/releases/tag/7.2.2</url>
        </release>
        <release version="7.2.1" date="2020-09-20">
            <description>
                <p>Preference pages structure was reorganized (in the standalone and plugin versions)</p>
                <p>Database navigator:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>Filters now support masks escape (_ and % characters)</li>
                    <li>Connection state icons were replaced and adapted to dark themes</li>
                </ul>
                <p>SQL Editor: editor tab title now can include active database/schema name</p>
                <p>MySQL: driver "MySQL 8" is now the default driver. "MySQL 5" driver can be used for older server versions.</p>
                <p>Oracle: tables/views load performance was improved on some systems</p>
                <p>PostgreSQL:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>Latest PostGIS driver mapping was added</li>
                    <li>Geometry data types export was improved (proper SQL format + SRID)</li>
                    <li>Hidden databases can be loaded in the database navigater</li>
                </ul>
                <p>CockroarchDB: role manager was fixed</p>
                <p>DB2: runstats utility support was fixed (wrong syntax)</p>
                <p>SQL Server: extra T-SQL dialect keywords were added</p>
                <p>CUBRID driver configuration was fixed</p>
                <p>Several UI freeze issues were fixed (deadlocks)</p>
                <p>Import from CSV/XLSX:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>Wrong rows can be skipped (with disabled "Batch import" option)</li>
                    <li>Import parameters documentation was updated</li>
                </ul>
                <p>Several minor bugs were fixed (NPE and UI glitches)</p>
            </description>
            <url>https://github.com/dbeaver/dbeaver/releases/tag/7.2.1</url>
        </release>
        <release version="7.2.0" date="2020-08-30">
            <description>
                <p>Major changes since 7.1:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>Simplified database structure view was added</li>
                    <li>Database maintenance tools can be saved as tasks now</li>
                    <li>Table and schema size statistics were added in the database navigator</li>
                    <li>Import from multiple CSV files was added. Files can be imported into new or existing tables</li>
                    <li>Many problems with UI freeze on disconnect or query cancel were fixed</li>
                    <li>Database navigator rendering was redesigned</li>
                    <li>A number of problems with keyboard shortcuts were fixed</li>
                    <li>Git integration was improved: now we show file status in the Project Explorer view</li>
                    <li>New database drivers were added: YugabyteDB and SQreamDB</li>
                </ul>
                <p>Changes since 7.1.5:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>Problem with database list load was fixed (PostgreSQL, Redshift, MySQL, Oracle, SQL Server)</li>
                    <li>Metadata editor: edit property form rendering was improved (non-applicable fields are hidden)</li>
                    <li>Performance for table statistics reading was improved</li>
                    <li>Data viewer: Column ordering was fixed (for custom SQL queries). UUID transform: version 2 support was added</li>
                    <li>Default database name and default user name were added for many database drivers</li>
                    <li>Data export: custom data type formatting support was fixed</li>
                    <li>PostgreSQL: Cursor fetch was fixed. Native client was upgraded to version 12. Table OID support was fixed (PG 12). PgPass parser was improved (support for escaped characters was added).</li>
                    <li>Oracle: Materialized view comment editor was fixed. View definition reading was fixed (for non-DBA users). Table reading now uses DBA views (optional). Profile resources metadata reading was fixed.</li>
                    <li>MariaDB/MySQL: table column resolving was fixed</li>
                    <li>CockroachDB: connectivity problem was fixed</li>
                    <li>Greenplum: Metadata search was fixed (for procedures). Table metadata reading was fixed.</li>
                    <li>Dark theme support was improved (tab folders, toolbars)</li>
                    <li>A large number of minor UI bugfixes</li>
                </ul>
            </description>
            <url>https://github.com/dbeaver/dbeaver/releases/tag/7.2.0</url>
        </release>
        </releases>
    <content_rating type="oars-1.1"/>
</component>