<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<component type="desktop">
    <id>io.dbeaver.DBeaverCommunity</id>
    <launchable type="desktop-id">io.dbeaver.DBeaverCommunity.desktop</launchable>
    <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
    <project_license>Apache-2.0</project_license>
    <name>DBeaver Community</name>
    <url type="homepage">https://dbeaver.io</url>
    <summary>Universal Database Manager.</summary>
    <description>
        <p>Free multi-platform database tool for developers, SQL programmers, database administrators and analysts. Supports all popular databases: MySQL, PostgreSQL, MariaDB, SQLite, Oracle, DB2, SQL Server, Sybase, MS Access, Teradata, Firebird, Derby, etc.</p>
        <p>This is the official build of DBeaver, packaged into a Flatpak. This repackaging is not supported by DBeaver Community Edition.</p>
    </description>
    <screenshots>
        <screenshot type="default">
            <image>https://i.imgur.com/AiCETK9.png</image>
            <caption>Query properties overview</caption>
        </screenshot>
        <screenshot>
            <image>https://i.imgur.com/5S6ohkF.png</image>
            <caption>Query properties overview</caption>
        </screenshot>
        <screenshot>
            <image>https://i.imgur.com/0a4OyvB.png</image>
            <caption>Query search overview</caption>
        </screenshot>
        <screenshot>
            <image>https://i.imgur.com/neoEtsF.png</image>
            <caption>ER Diagram Example</caption>
        </screenshot>
    </screenshots>
    <releases>
        <release version="7.1.3" date="2020-07-19">
            <description>
                <ul style-type="none">
                    <li>Spatial presentation: tooltips rendering was fixed</li>
                    <li>DB2: UI tools were converted into database tasks</li>
                    <li>MySQL/MariaDB: database restore was fixed (binary data corruption)</li>
                    <li>PostgreSQL: data type DDL was improved + comment edit support was added</li>
                    <li>Oracle: problem with connect as SYSDBA was fixed</li>
                    <li>Exasol: (thaks to @Sargul)</li>
                    <li>-  Database error type discovery was added (proper handle of "connection lost" errors)</li>
                    <li>-  Metadata read performance was improved</li>
                    <li>Googlee Spanner: official driver configuration was added (thanks to @olavloite)</li>
                    <li>Simple view mode was fixed (redundant database objects were hidden)</li>
                    <li>Proxy configuration UI was fixed</li>
                    <li>MacOS installer was fixed (potential vulnerability was removed, thanks to @De4dCr0w)</li>
                    <li>Tasks management: error handing was improved (for deleted tables)</li>
                    <li>We reverted to Eeclipse 2020-03 platform (it resolves a set of UI glitches on some platforms)</li>
                    <li>A few minor UI and database-specific bugs were fixed</li>
                </ul>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release version="7.1.2" date="2020-07-05">
            <description>
                <p>Data viewer:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>Now we refresh entire row after cell value update (handy if you have triggers)</li>
                    <li>Generate SQL context menu was fixed</li>
                    <li>Horizontal scroll with mouse wheel support was added</li>
                    <li>Export data in source code (PHP arrays) format was added</li>
                    <li>Bug with Ctrl+Backspace handler was fixed</li>
                </ul>
                <p>SQL Editor:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>Query cancel handler was improved (problem with UI stuck was fixed)</li>
                    <li>Now we show query information in the result tab tooltip</li>
                    <li>Query parser was fixed (active query extraction for Ctrl+Enter action)</li>
                    <li>Template variables (${word_selection} and ${line_selection}) support was fixed</li>
                </ul>
                <p>Navigator:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>Icons for "Create object" actions were fixed</li>
                    <li>Main menu File items were reordered</li>
                    <li>Heading and trailing spaces trim was added to all edit dialogs/panels</li>
                </ul>
                <p>Session manager: problem with multiple windows was fixed.
                SQL Server: Database tools (index rebuild, triggers disable) were redesigned.
                Firebird: new table and table column creation was fixed.
                PostgreSQL: Table partition DDL was fixed.
                MySQL: CHECK constraints edit support was added</p>
                <p>Oracle:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>Table statistics read was fixed</li>
                    <li>Schema indexes folder was added</li>
                    <li>Check constraints editor was added</li>
                    <li>Trigger status icon was fixed</li>
                </ul>
                <p>Exasol: (thanks to @Sargul)</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>Metadata read performance was improved</li>
                    <li>Metadata search support was added</li>
                    <li>Table references</li>
                    <li>Index create DDL was fixed</li>
                    <li>Table statistics read performance was improved</li>
                </ul>
                <p>Redshift: driver download was fixed.
                SQreamDB driver was added.
                YugabyteDB driver was added.
                We upgraded Eclipse platform version to 2020-06. It affects dark theme and General preferences and fixes several minor bugs</p>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release version="7.1.1" date="2020-06-21">
            <description>
                <p>Database navigator:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>Connection type highlighting was redesigned</li>
                    <li>Simple view support was improved</li>
                    <li>"Force object refresh on editor open" action was fixed</li>
                    <li>Main toolbar UIX was improved (no disabled selectors)</li>
                    <li>Database tools context menu was fixed</li>
                </ul>
                <p>Table statistics:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>Rendering problems (redraw on scrolling) were fixed</li>
                    <li>Performance problems were fixed</li>
                    <li>SQL Server support was added</li>
                </ul>
                <p>Data viewer:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>Wrong value extraction was fixed for expression aliases which conflict with table column names</li>
                    <li>Dictionary values separator configuration was added</li>
                    <li>Row coloring: support of gradient coloring for read-only columns was added</li>
                    <li>Data formatter:</li>
                    <li>Action "reset to default" was fixed in preferences</li>
                    <li>Preference changes are immediately applied to open data editors</li>
                </ul>
                <p>SQL editor:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>Results tab rename was fixed (now we save tab title between results refresh)</li>
                    <li>Parser of multiple SQL queries on a single line was fixed</li>
                    <li>Execution plan explain operation cancel was implemented</li>
                    <li>Coloring of numbers in scientific notation was fixed</li>
                    <li>Paste from source code: \n and \r characters handle was fixed (now we use proper line feeds)</li>
                    <li>Stored procedures call generation was fixed</li>
                </ul>
                <p>Object editor: "reject changes" and command undo/redo command were fixed
                Data import: open target table on finish
                Data migration: DDL generation was improved (apply the same column data type when source and target databases use the same driver)
                Database tasks: PostgreSQL, MySQL and Oracle tools now can be saved as tasks
                SSH configurator: UI controls layout was fixed
                Database driver edit dialog was fixed (legacy driver option is disabled by default)</p>
                <p>MySQL:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>User permission management was fixed (FLUSH PRIVILEGES is not needed for newer server versions)</li>
                    <li>Unsigned INT and BIGINT data types support was added</li>
                </ul>
                <p>Oracle:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>Numeric data type modifiers (scale/precision) rendering was fixed</li>
                    <li>Materialized views read/create and delete was fixed (mviews were removed from table list)</li>
                </ul>
                <p>PostgreSQL:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>Vacuum tool was improved (run in auto-commit mode)</li>
                    <li>List of reserved keywords was updated</li>
                </ul>
                <p>Redshift: View with no schema binding support was added</p>
                <p>SQL Server: timestamp columns were marked as auto-generated</p>
                <p>Big number of minor UI and database-specific bugs were fixed</p>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release version="7.1.0" date="2020-05-31">
            <description>
                <ul>
                    <li>It has been hard quarantine time. But we haven’t stopped development process.</li>
                    <li>And now, it’s time for the new minor release 7.1.0.</li>
                    <li>Thank you to our new and old contributors. Stay well and healthy!</li>
                    <li> Database navigator:</li>
                    <li>     Statistics view (table sizes) was added</li>
                    <li>     Connection coloring was redesigned</li>
                    <li>     Connection host name tip was added</li>
                    <li> Data viewer:</li>
                    <li>     Ref cursor panel viewer was added</li>
                    <li>     Columns sort settings save/load was added</li>
                    <li>     Data export in HTML format was fixed (styles)</li>
                    <li> SQL editor:</li>
                    <li>     Function call formatting was improved</li>
                    <li>     Table alias generation was fixed (for unicode/numeric table names)</li>
                    <li> PostgreSQL:</li>
                    <li>     Ref cursors refresh support was added</li>
                    <li>     Table and schema statistics was added</li>
                    <li>     Table comment and rules were added to DDL</li>
                    <li> Oracle:</li>
                    <li>     Metadata search was fixed</li>
                    <li>     Java source read was fixed</li>
                    <li> ODBC driver download was fixed</li>
                    <li> Exasol: metadata edit dialogs were redesigned</li>
                    <li> Clickhouse: table statistics was added</li>
                    <li> Firebird: view editor was fixed</li>
                    <li> Plain HTTP driver repositories (Maven or direct links) were replaced or removed</li>
                    <li> Big number of minor UI and database-specific bugs were fixed</li>
                </ul>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release version="7.0.5" date="2020-05-17">
            <description>
                <ul>
                    <li> Data viewer:</li>
                    <li>     Pin (aka "freeze") column feature was added</li>
                    <li>     Float (32bit) data type render was fixed (MySQL)</li>
                    <li>     Plaintext renderer was fixed (binary values representation)</li>
                    <li>     Filter value auto-complete was fixed (clipboard paste support)</li>
                    <li>     Issue with "order by table column + column alias" was fixed</li>
                    <li> SQL editor:</li>
                    <li>     Script close prompt was fixed</li>
                    <li>     Hyperlinks now contain procedure parameters</li>
                    <li>     Script selector panel positioning was fixed</li>
                    <li>     Execute in new tab: new tabs opening was fixed</li>
                    <li>     SQL format preferences page was improved</li>
                    <li>     SQL formatting was fixed (line feeds after brackets)</li>
                    <li>     SQL console title was fixed (source object name was added)</li>
                    <li> Non-https Maven repositories and driver links were removed</li>
                    <li> PostgreSQL:</li>
                    <li>     Added parameters to the SQL execution plan explain (ANALYSE is optional)</li>
                    <li>     Database backup  was fixed on Linux/MacOS (proper table names quoting)</li>
                    <li>     Table DDL was fixed (show table comment)</li>
                    <li>     Sequence DDL was fixed (START parameter)</li>
                    <li>     Object dependencies now contain links on dependent/depending object</li>
                    <li>     Permission/role editors were fixed (roles are sorted by name now)</li>
                    <li>     SQL auto-completion fixed for older PG (&lt;= 8.4)</li>
                    <li> Oracle: unique key detection was fixed</li>
                    <li> DB2:</li>
                    <li>     FOR BIT DATA columns support was fixed (show value as binary)</li>
                    <li>     Native SQL dialect support was improved (BEGIN/END)</li>
                    <li> SQLite: ROWID pseudo-column support was added (as unique key)</li>
                    <li> Many other minor bug fixes and improvements</li>
                </ul>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release version="7.0.4" date="2020-05-03">
            <description>
                <ul>
                    <li> SQL editor:</li>
                    <li>     Format now formats active query by default</li>
                    <li>     Matching brackets highlighting was improved</li>
                    <li> Data viewer:</li>
                    <li>     Find/replace highlighting and scrolling was fixed</li>
                    <li>     Data filter save was fixed (problem with quoted column names)</li>
                    <li>     Auto-completion in data filter now can be disabled</li>
                    <li> Object editor: refresh button in bottom toolbar was unified for all pages</li>
                    <li> Dark theme support improved (connection type colors)</li>
                    <li> New connection wizard was fixed (problem with quick driver selector)</li>
                    <li> Driver editor dialog was improved:</li>
                    <li>     Extra properties save was fixed</li>
                    <li>     Legacy drivers support was added</li>
                    <li> Git extension packaging was fixed (older Eclipse versions support)</li>
                    <li> Derby: new database create was fixed</li>
                    <li> Firebird: system objects hide/show was fixed (determine system flag from fro meta table)</li>
                    <li> MySQL:</li>
                    <li>     Read-only connections support was fixed (SQL editors)</li>
                    <li>     Query execution plan explain was fixed</li>
                    <li> Oracle:</li>
                    <li>     Driver configuration was fixed (typo in Maven artifact name)</li>
                    <li>     Java classes source viewer was added</li>
                    <li>     Materialized view DDL read was fixed</li>
                    <li>     PL/SQL parser was fixed (CASE/WHEN/END)</li>
                    <li> PostgreSQL:</li>
                    <li>     search_path update was fixed</li>
                    <li>     Numeric values rendering was fixed</li>
                    <li> Redshift: SOCKS proxy support was fixed</li>
                    <li> SQL Server: table DDL generation was fixed (column type names)</li>
                    <li> SQLite: foreign key metadata read was fixed (FKs with no name)</li>
                    <li> Portuguese (BR) localization was added (thanks to @wellesximenes)</li>
                    <li> Many minor bug fixes and improvements</li>
                </ul>
            </description>
        </release>
    </releases>
    <content_rating type="oars-1.1" />
</component>