<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<component type="desktop">
    <id>io.dbeaver.DBeaverCommunity</id>
    <launchable type="desktop-id">io.dbeaver.DBeaverCommunity.desktop</launchable>
    <metadata_license>CC0-1.0</metadata_license>
    <project_license>Apache-2.0</project_license>
    <name>DBeaver Community</name>
    <url type="homepage">https://dbeaver.io</url>
    <summary>Universal Database Manager.</summary>
    <description>
        <p>Free multi-platform database tool for developers, SQL programmers, database administrators and analysts. Supports all popular databases: MySQL, PostgreSQL, MariaDB, SQLite, Oracle, DB2, SQL Server, Sybase, MS Access, Teradata, Firebird, Derby, etc.</p>
        <p>This is the official build of DBeaver, packaged into a Flatpak. This repackaging is not supported by DBeaver Community Edition.</p>
    </description>
    <screenshots>
        <screenshot type="default">
            <image>https://i.imgur.com/AiCETK9.png</image>
            <caption>Query Editor overview</caption>
        </screenshot>
        <screenshot>
            <image>https://i.imgur.com/5S6ohkF.png</image>
            <caption>Query Editor overview</caption>
        </screenshot>
        <screenshot>
            <image>https://i.imgur.com/0a4OyvB.png</image>
            <caption>Query Editor overview</caption>
        </screenshot>
    </screenshots>
    <releases>
        <release version="6.2.0" date="2019-09-08">
            <description>
                <ul>
                    <li>- Data viewer:</li>
                    <li>    - JSON highlighting/formatting was added</li>
                    <li>    - Select/deselect rows with alt+click was improved</li>
                    <li>    - Reference panel now supports virtual foreign keys</li>
                    <li>    - "Set to default value" action was fixed (for timestamp columns)</li>
                    <li>    - Dictionary read was fixed</li>
                    <li>- ERD:</li>
                    <li>    - Table/schema diagram edit is now supported</li>
                    <li>    - Virtual foreign keys support was added</li>
                    <li>- Database navigator:</li>
                    <li>    - Transactions tracking was improved (+now commit/rollback actions are always active)</li>
                    <li>    - Cross-project connections copy-paste and drag-n-drop was fixed</li>
                    <li>    - Navigator tree state save (and restore on restart) was added (thanks to loro2)</li>
                    <li>    - Columns reordering was fixed</li>
                    <li>    - Global filters configuration was fixed</li>
                    <li>    - Connection permissions are now supported in connection type (prod, dev, test)</li>
                    <li>- SQL editor:</li>
                    <li>    - Query execution time logging was fixed</li>
                    <li>    - Generate SQL dialog was improved (FQ names, copy to clipboard)</li>
                    <li>    - Script selector panel UI was fixed</li>
                    <li>    - Variables binding now can be skipped for a query/script</li>
                    <li>    - JDBC fetch size now set for custom SQL queries</li>
                    <li>- Data export now reuses SQL editor connection</li>
                    <li>- Metadata editor: columns drop was fixed</li>
                    <li>- SQL Server:</li>
                    <li>    - NVARCHAR/NCHAR length calculation was fixed</li>
                    <li>    - Column default value edit support was added</li>
                    <li>    - DDL for TEXT/NTEXT data types was fixed</li>
                    <li>- PostgreSQL:</li>
                    <li>    - Driver now uses URL template (by default)</li>
                    <li>    - Column comments for new tables now saved properly</li>
                    <li>- SQL Server Data Warehouse support was added</li>
                    <li>- MySQL: bit stream data type support was fixed</li>
                    <li>- CockroachDB: table metadata read was fixed</li>
                    <li>- Apache Derby driver was upgraded</li>
                    <li>- Teradata: multiple resultsets support was added</li>
                    <li>- Test connection dialog was redesigned</li>
                    <li>- Driver libraries cache was fixed (re-download of Maven artifacts)</li>
                    <li>- Widows registry reading was fixed (Java 8 compatibility)</li>
                    <li>- Many other minor bugs were fixed</li>
                </ul>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release version="6.1.5" date="2019-08-18">
            <description>
                <ul>
                    <li>- Data viewer:</li>
                    <li>    - Virtual primary/foreign keys editors were enhanced</li>
                    <li>    - Problem with filters on data refresh was fixed</li>
                    <li>    - Added confirmation dialog before opened result tabs closing</li>
                    <li>    - Problem with missing updated row count (in script mode) was fixed</li>
                    <li>    - References panel now remembers last FK/reference selection</li>
                    <li>    - Value view panel now supports Find/Replace</li>
                    <li>    - Float values rendering was fixed (numbers rounding is disabled by default)</li>
                    <li>- Data transfer:</li>
                    <li>    - Save of previous target container selections was added</li>
                    <li>    - Export of tables/queries with complex data types (structs, objects) was improved</li>
                    <li>- Connection management:</li>
                    <li>    - Connection permissions config was added (restrictions of data/metadata changes for a particular connection or connection type)</li>
                    <li>    - Problem with bootstrap queries and auto-commit state save/load was fixed</li>
                    <li>    - Multi-project support was improved (use selected project for new connections)</li>
                    <li>    - Support of empty database passwords was added</li>
                    <li>    - Copy/paste and drag-n-drop connections between different projects was fixed</li>
                    <li>- Database navigator:</li>
                    <li>    - Default double-click behavior configuration was added (view properties/data/erd)</li>
                    <li>    - Object edit dialogs are properly sized now (problem with too small dialog window was fixed)</li>
                    <li>    - Connection type coloring in the main toolbar is back</li>
                    <li>    - DBeaver toolbars visibility was fixed (for Eclipse plugin version)</li>
                    <li>- New DBeaver version automatic downloading (optional) was added</li>
                    <li>- MySQL:</li>
                    <li>    - Datetime columns edit was fixed. Problems with timezone were fixed.</li>
                    <li>    - Legacy MySQL &lt;4 driver was added (again)</li>
                    <li>- PostgreSQL:</li>
                    <li>    - Automatic transaction error recovery was added (famous "current transaction is aborted" error)</li>
                    <li>    - Partition management was added (partition create/drop)</li>
                    <li>    - Support of VACUUM tool for older PG version was fixed</li>
                    <li>    - Enum items order was fixed (in metadata editor)</li>
                    <li>    - Legacy PostgreSQL &lt;= 8 driver was added</li>
                    <li>- SQL Server: index DDL was improved (now it contains all index properties)</li>
                    <li>- Redshift: table DDL generation was fixed ("diststyle AUTO" and other improvements)</li>
                    <li>- Hive: struct/array data types support was added</li>
                    <li>- Presto: array data types support was fixed</li>
                    <li>- DB2 i: routine list reading was fixed</li>
                    <li>- We have migrated to the Eclipse 2019-06 platform (fixes many minor UI bugs on Linux)</li>
                    <li>- Many other minor bugs were fixed</li>
                </ul>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release version="6.1.4" date="2019-08-04">
            <description>
                <ul>
                    <li> - Many problems with workspace migration were fixed</li>
                    <li> - Data viewer:</li>
                    <li>     - UI look and feel was significantly improved</li>
                    <li>     - New interface for rows/columns coloring</li>
                    <li>     - Logical foreign key creation was simplified</li>
                    <li>     - Many bugs were fixed in References panel rendering</li>
                    <li>     - Column filters UI was fixed (dups, dictionary reading errors)</li>
                    <li>     - Unique key detection was fixed (use indexes with nullable columns if no other identifiers found)</li>
                    <li> - Entiy diagrams: logical foreign keys can be created/deleted right in the diagram editor</li>
                    <li> - Data transfer: auto-generated (identity) columns handler was added</li>
                    <li> - DDL generation: now we generate tables DDL according to their foreign keys order</li>
                    <li> - Geometry viewer: simple (flat) geometry support was added</li>
                    <li> - Execution log: reading of row count for DML statements was fixed</li>
                    <li> - SQL Editor:</li>
                    <li>     - SQL formatter was fixed (DECLARE statements)</li>
                    <li>     - Copy SQL to Java code was improved (thanks to loro2)</li>
                    <li> - PostgreSQL:</li>
                    <li>     - Array data type handler was fixed</li>
                    <li>     - Indexes metadata reading was fixed</li>
                    <li>     - Execution plan visualization was fixed for CTE nodes</li>
                    <li> - SQL Server:</li>
                    <li>     - Support of identity columns creation was added</li>
                    <li>     - Session manager was fixed</li>
                    <li> - Oracle:</li>
                    <li>     - Scheduled jobs metadata reading was fixed</li>
                    <li>     - Session management was fixed for RAC mode</li>
                    <li> - Firebird: views and indexes metadata reading was fixed</li>
                    <li> - Apache Hive: many bugfixes related to complex (struct/array) data types handling</li>
                    <li> - Apache Drill: driver was fixed (missing JDK modules were added)</li>
                    <li> - Many other minor UI bugs were fixed</li>
                </ul>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release version="6.1.3" date="2019-07-22">
            <description>
                <ul>
                    <li>New project configuration format was implemented. Main advantages:</li>
                    <li>    - Better security (now we keep user credentials separately)</li>
                    <li>    - Better support for version control systems (e.g. Git)</li>
                    <li>    - Now we use standard (OS-specific) directories for configuration location</li>
                    <li>Major features:</li>
                    <li>    - Logical foreign keys</li>
                    <li>    - Data viewer: "References" panel was added (browse values by foreign and reference keys)</li>
                    <li>    - Network profiles support was added: you may configure SSH/Proxy settings once and reuse them for any number of connections</li>
                    <li>Other:</li>
                    <li>    - Connection page was redesigned</li>
                    <li>    - Data viewer filter panel UI was improved</li>
                    <li>    - Snowflake: procedures DDL, connection page fix</li>
                    <li>    - Google Spanned database support was added</li>
                    <li>    - PostgreSQL: struct/array data types support was fixed</li>
                    <li>    - MySQL: privileges viewer was fixed (global privileges grant/revoke)</li>
                    <li>    - DB2 i: procedure list and DDL reading was fixed</li>
                    <li>    - Many minor UI bugs were fixed</li>
                </ul>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release version="6.1.2" date="2019-07-07">
            <description>
                <ul>
                    <li>- Git integration:</li>
                    <li>    - Create projects in remote repositories</li>
                    <li>    - Pull/commit/push automation from the DBeaver perspective</li>
                    <li>    - Integrate existing projectys with Git repositories</li>
                    <li>- Problem with SSH and SSL connections was solved</li>
                    <li>- Problem with missing legacy character encoding was fixed</li>
                    <li>- Data editor:</li>
                    <li>    - "Delete cascade" feature was added</li>
                    <li>    - Problem with column order was fixed (when result contains multiple columns with the same name)</li>
                    <li>    - Problem with duplicated values in column filters was fixed</li>
                    <li>    - "Default" values were added for numbers, strings and booleans</li>
                    <li>- Data transfer:</li>
                    <li>    - Export to a single file was fixed</li>
                    <li>    - TXT format: extra options were added</li>
                    <li>    - CSV import: timestamp columns parser was fixed</li>
                    <li>- PostgeSQL:</li>
                    <li>    - Extensions management was added</li>
                    <li>    - Partitions DDL was added</li>
                    <li>    - Partitions create/drop support was added</li>
                    <li>    - Object description reading was fixed (+ problem with duplicated objects was solved)</li>
                    <li>    - Complex data types rendering was fixed</li>
                    <li>    - float4 data type support was fixed (wrong value render)</li>
                    <li>- Greenplum: ERD renderer was fixed</li>
                    <li>- Orclele:</li>
                    <li>    - Problem with read-only tables was fixed (for some Oracle versions)</li>
                    <li>    - View management: problem with semicolons was fixed</li>
                    <li>- DB2 for iSeries:</li>
                    <li>    - Procedures DDL was added</li>
                    <li>    - Problem with schema list reading  was fixed</li>
                    <li>- Generic driver (SQLite and others): problem with view create command was fixed</li>
                    <li>    - Plenty of minor UI bugs were fixed</li>
                </ul>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release version="6.1.1" date="2019-06-24">
            <description>
                <ul>
                    <li>- We have migrated to Java11 (Windows and MacOS bundled JRE is OpenJDK 11.0.3)</li>
                    <li>- ERD: diagram refresh fixed (do not re-layout elements)</li>
                    <li>- ERD: support of zoom with mouse wheel was added</li>
                    <li>- PostgreSQL: ref cursor data type support was fixed</li>
                    <li>- Oracle: bootstrap queries execute was fixed</li>
                    <li>- DB2 for iSeries, DB2 for z/OS: schema list reading was fixed</li>
                    <li>- SQLite: datetime columns support was fixed</li>
                    <li>- SAP HANA: triggers support was added (read-only)</li>
                    <li>- Data views: calc panel was fixed (min/max functions evaluation)</li>
                </ul>
            </description>
        </release>
        </releases>
    <content_rating type="oars-1.1"/>
</component>
